Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ dominikamarcinkowski (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Content Marketing Social Media Corporate Blogging

Languages

Englisch (Full Professional)

Deutsch (Native or Bilingual)

Polnisch (Limited Working)

Certifications

Social Media, Mobile Marketing and Digital Strategy

Advanced Search Engine Optimization(SEO) Certification Training

Advanced Pay Per Click (PPC)

Conversion and Strategy

Advanced Social Media Certification Training

Honors-Awards

Nomination for PR Report's #30u30 2019

Dominika Marcinkowski

Digital Marketer & Content Creator with focus on Social Media | #30u30 2019 @PRReport

Berlin

Summary

Short human on a mission to grow. In general, not just in terms of career.

German native speaker who is experienced in various fields of marketing such as social media, content production, event management, PR, digital marketing, thought leadership communication, and all the other cool buzzwords people like to hear. I started in a small artist agency, moved then to a Berlin-based startup followed by a big IT corporation. What I've learned during this time – apart from all the great marketing skills? Having good people around you is important, don't take everything too seriously and from time to time, do your job and be good in it. At the moment, I'm working with field marketing, sales, and executives to turn their and the company's social voices into a powerful asset to drive visibility and revenue. Also, the Gallup StrengthsFinder test says I'm whimsical. Wanna swipe right?

Experience

TLGG
Content Creative
August 2021 - Present (8 months)
Berlin, Germany

Hewlett Packard Enterprise Social Media Lead April 2018 - July 2021 (3 years 4 months) Wroclaw, Lower Silesian District, Poland

- Leading the social media communication for DACH markets plus project related collaborations on other global channels
- Content creation, editing, and localising (e.g. copy, visuals, gifs, short blog formats) on different strategic levels such as brand, thought leadership,

employees advocacy for various channels & technology sectors in English & German

- Collaborating with regional marketing, comms, SEO, web marketing, sales, and executives regarding strategy & content
- On-site social media support at events by leveraging the company's key messages in an engaging way
- Reporting & analysis of content performance for events or executed campaigns
- Social listening & daily media monitoring to identify trending topics, relevant conversations, and influential leaders

HeavenHR

1 year 4 months

Junior Marketing Manager October 2016 - August 2017 (11 months)

- Event & Project Management: Organize HeavenHR Speaker Series on a regular basis and prepare fair attendance
- Content Production: Produce customer-driven content for website, blog, product and several campaigns
- Create and manage the company's corporate newsletter in order to retain customer's loyalty and generate warm leads
- Conception and creation of marketing material with a team of designers
- Manage social media channels (Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter, Instagram)
- Support in paid media activities (Google Adwords, Facebook Advertising)
- Collaborative work with several departments such as Sales, Customer Service, Design, Product and the Management

Marketing & Content Working Student August 2016 - September 2016 (2 months) Berlin Area, Germany

Marketing & Content Intern May 2016 - August 2016 (4 months)

Berlin Area, Germany

- Content creation for blog, website, marketing campaigns & materials
- Manage the German blog, which includes researching, producing and SEO optimizing blog posts
- Assist & support of several marketing activities

Artist Network

PR & Content Marketing Intern October 2015 - March 2016 (6 months)

Berlin Area, Germany

- Content creation for newsletter, website and social media channels
- Support in concept creation for customers with focus on a suitable brand communication
- Support in organizing several projects such as events during the Fashion Week, Berlinale or in-house video projects
- Research and brainstorming on current trends, events and influencer network

VHS Duisburg

PR & Communication Intern

August 2014 - September 2014 (2 months)

Duisburg Area, Germany

- Coordination, planning and project assistance for several events in the education segment
- Support and job shadowing in the fields of press and public relations
- Text production and revision in context of the new website (CMS)
- Research work and several other tasks for daily operations

3rd "Duisburger Weiterbildungstag" I Project Assistance

- Assistance in planning and implementing of the VHS presentation before, during and after the event
- Editorial co-creation of flyer and posters

Education

Uniwersytet Wrocławski

Master of Arts - MA, Communication Management · (2017 - 2019)

Universität Siegen

Bachelor's Degree, Language and Communication/ Economics (2011 - 2015)

University of Newcastle

Linguistics, Communication · (2013 - 2014)